[Music]
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome to
price and Taska Advanced
Training till now I published 42 YouTube
videos covering basic level Concepts
intermediate level Concepts and advanced
level
Concepts from this lesson onwards I'm
going to start publishing 40 different
YouTube
videos to cover some of the realtime
scenarios while automating the test
cases by using trient Taska basically in
real time when you are working on a
project in an organization you're going
to face lot of obstacles while
automating your test cases so I'm going
to start publishing the YouTube
videos to show you how can we automate
the test cases whenever you encounter
different types of
obstacles in real time please do
subscribe to the channel click on Bell
icon you'll receive notifications
whenever I publish more videos thank you
this is lesson 43 in terms of percentage
Taska overall training or this is lesson
one in terms of realtime scenario
automation so in this lesson I'm going
to teach you how can we automate a test
case when you encounter an
obstacle with elements with same IDs
let's first understand what is the
obstacle and how can we solve that
obstacle to automate your test case
let's go back to our Chrome
[Music]
browser so this is your obstacle list
that is provided by trient tasa I'm
going to leave this URL in the comment
box so that you can access this obstacle
list so what is our first obstacle my
first obstacle is this
one so what does this obstacle means
so we have to automate a test step that
clicks on the button labeled click me if
you see on the screen you have two
buttons one is don't another one is
Click
me so these two buttons are on the
screen and you need to click on click me
right side
button so here these two buttons have
similar IDs and and how can we solve by
using trient tasa to automate this test
case so this is my trient tasa and here
we're going to
start scanning the application so I have
created a module called obstacles so
it's not a module it's a folder within
the module so now I'm going to right
click on this
obstacles and then start scanning the
application so here
I'm going to select the application that
I would like to
automate so this is our application
right so where we have to solve this
problem and click on
scan so let me expand this one if you
see on the screen we have two buttons
one is don't and click me right so these
two are those buttons don't and click me
if you select this click me you can see
the properties of that button if you see
the properties of that button ID is the
property do not use ID and it also
having a tag as the property right it is
identifying this clickme object by using
these two properties let's go and see
don't button this don't button also have
ID and and tag and if You observe
closely the ID property is same as this
earlier click me button do not use ID
whereas in Click me button also has do
not use ID that
means if you capture this particular
object by using tasar it's not going to
uniquely identify let's select this
click me button and if you see here this
is highlighting in orange color that
means the selected item is not
unique so what should we do to make this
button
unique so there are two
ways one is either you can start using
the inner text if you see here this is
your inner text for this what is the
inner text click me let's go and see in
don't button for don't button
your inner text is don't that means I
can add an additional property called
inner text to make this button unique so
let's add this okay let's add this inner
text as soon as I add now you see here
the selected item is unique that means
now the selected item is
unique whenever you have multiple
objects objects having the same
property you can
use an alternative property to identify
the object
uniquely and
here you can also expand the filters
here to see their
parent objects as well there is another
way where you can also use the parent
object but that concept I'm going to
cover in our upcoming lessons so for now
let's go with the alternative property
to identify the object
uniquely so now let us rename this
module as obstacle
name as same as your obstacle name the
obstacle
as225 so I'm going to play paste this
one so it's good practice to rename the
module so that you can identify the
module easily and here your button name
makes sense I need not to rename the
button name if you want I can rename the
button as well so the best practice is
you should have the naming
convention in a such a way that you
should be able to identify the objects
or naming of the objects very easily now
let us say save this as soon as I save a
module will be created and close this
now let's go back to present stasa I can
see here now click me button is added
under a module called obstacle #
22505 so now let us create a test case
for this right click and then create a
folder
called obstacles
obstacles now under this folder let us
create our first test case and then name
this as obstacle #
22505 and now let's drag this module and
drop
here and now here to click this
particular button on screen right there
are two ways
either you can select click keyboard
option so what it does this
actually takes the keyboard action that
means it uses the mouse to click on that
particular button so which is not
recommended because it is very time
consuming and your performance of the
application comes down your performance
of the tasar comes down and it is very
slow so tritis
recommends to not use click function
here instead you can
use this one you need to pass X to click
on any
object and now let us run this
particular test case and see it's going
to click on the button which is on the
right
side so just right click and run in
scratch so now it's clicked on the
button but we could not understand it
clicked on which button right I can do
one thing I can introduce click option
here
right click what it does it actually
moves the cursor onto the button so that
you can understand it is clicking on
which button let's run this
again so now you can see it is clicking
on click me button so your automation
problem is
solved so you can you can see here your
test results are
passed so once you complete your test
case design and automation it's a best
practice to use the workstate column to
mark it as completed and save your test
case so this is how you can solve the
challenge of elements that are having
the same
property if you have any queries leave
your queries in the comment box I'll try
to respond to your
queries hope you all understand how can
we solve the challenge that you may
encounter in real time while automating
your test
cases please do subscribe to the channel
click on Bell icon you'll receive
notification whenever I publish more
videos thank you
[Music]